<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paul Sathuluri</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Paul Sathuluri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reticulate: R &amp; Python</title>
      <link>/post/2020/12/11/reticulate-r-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/12/11/reticulate-r-python/</guid>
      <description>What is Reticulate? Reticulate is a cool package that lets R communicate with Python. It converts the R objects types into their equivalent Python types and vice versa, which lets us do some pretty neat things.
 Reticulate in Action For instance, say you had a list in R of your favorite prime numbers (doesn’t everybody?). And say you also had a list of your favorite prime ministers (that’s kind of weird I’ll admit).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>Paul Sathuluri pvs297
Introduction The following dataset from 1980 contains 23972 observations and provides information on the budget share of food for Spanish households. Each entry in the dataset corresponds to a specific Spanish household. The data is sourced from the Journal of Applied Econometrics by means of the ‘Ecdat’ econometrics R package. The variables include wfood (percentage of total expenditure which the household has spent on food), totexp (total expenditure of the household), age (age of reference person in the household), size (number of people in the household), town (size of the town where the household is placed ranging from 1 for small towns to 5 for large towns), and sex (sex of reference person).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The datasets chosen for this project include Austin TX weather data sourced from WeatherUnderground.com, and Austin bike share trips sourced from the City of Austin. Both datasets were obtained from kaggle.com. I chose these datasets because I am familiar with them from a prior UT Austin DataHack competition, and the information and results are relevant to me as an Austin resident who uses the bicycle share program. Both of the datasets contain entries from December 21st, 2013 to July 31st, 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>  Check out some of my statistics projects below:
 Wrangling &amp;amp; Exploratory Data Analysis
 Modeling, Inference, Prediction
  -- </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>     </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
